Konvitz, Milton R. Papers /4039
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series II: Subject FIles, 1942-1986
  - American Council on Race Relations (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - American Culture (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Americans for Democratic Action (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - American: Economy, Affluence, and Census Profile of the 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - American Economic Foundation (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - American Ethical Union (Box 42, Folder 12)
    Also includes pamphlets from the Encampment for Citizenship and the Citizen Education Project
  - American Federation of Labor (AFL) (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO) (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - American Federation of Labor - History (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - American Freedom, 1955 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    1955, "Men Came to America to be Free, But" pamphlet by Freedom Agenda Committee of the Carrie Chapman Catt Memorial Fund, Incorporated
  - American Friends Service Committee (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - American: General, 1970-1974 (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - American Heritage Foundation (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - American Ideals, 1926-1954 (Box 42, Folder 20)
    Spring and fall syllabi from New York State School of Industrial and Labor relations (NYSSILR) course, 1953-1954; syllabus, University of Missouri, 1926.
  - American Immigration Conference, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 21)
    Minutes of Meeting of the Committee on Research and Studies, January 12, 1959
  - American Intellectual History (Box 42, Folder 22)
    1950 University of Buffalo syllabus
  - American Israeli Civil Liberties Union (Box 42, Folder 23)
  - American Jewish Committee (Box 42, Folder 24)
  - American Jewish Committee (Box 42, Folder 25)
  - American Jewish Committee - Institute of Human Relations (Box 42, Folder 26)
  - American Jewish Congress (Box 42, Folder 27)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1957-1972 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    Correspondence between Rabbi Yaakob Rosenberg and Marc A. Triebwasser about direction of American Jewish Congress; memorandum from Konvitz to Will Maslow, Executive Director of the American Jewish Congress, regarding Discriminatory school applications; correspondence between Konvitz and Joseph B. Robinson, Director of the American Jewish Congress Commission on Law and Social Action, about discriminatory school applications; memorandum from Will Maslow to Konvitz regarding Carrill's pending hiring of John Hatchett for black student advisor; memorandum to will Maslow from Konvitz regarding Discrimination by Cornell fraternities and sororities on the basis of race or religion; memorandum to Will Maslow from Konvitz regarding the legality of affirmative action policies for employees at Cornell; memorandum to Will Maslow from Konvitz regarding the origins of the quarterly journal, "Judaism"; confidential memorandum to the Executive Committee of the American Jewish Congress from Robert Gordis regarding the Origins of "Judaism"; Agenda Board of Directors Plenary meeting March 18-19, 1967; report, "The Legal Defense of Religious Liberty - The Strategy and Tactics of the A[merican] J[ewish] C[ongress, ACJ]" by Will Maslow, 1961; report, statement of the American Jewish Congress, 1957; draft resolutions for the American Jewish Congress, 1972; adopted resolutions of the American Jewish Congress, 1972; confidential report, "The Second Vatican Council's Declaration on Jews."
  - American Jewish League for Israel, 1957-1958 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    Draft of the Minyanim Plan proposal; draft of "A Faculty Council for Israel"
  - American Jewish Philosophical Society, 1961 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    Minutes of preliminary meeting, December 26, 1961
  - American Jewish Society for Service (Box 43, Folder 4)
    Hand-written note to Konvitz from Dan Hoffman on the possibility that the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations students could get credit for working for the Society
  - American Joint Distribution Committee (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - American Labor Education Service (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - American Library Association (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - American Management Association (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - American Philosophical Association, 1950-1980 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    1950 Resolution, Eastern Division; minutes of business meeting, 1980
  - American Political Science Association (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - American Politics (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - American Professors for Peace in the Middle East - material on a speech by James A. Michener, 1967 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Americanism (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - American Society of African Culture (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - American Society for Legal History (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - American Society for Political and Legal Philosophy (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - American Studies Association (ASA) (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - American Teacher (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - American Zionist Federation - Resolutions adopted, Biennial Convention, 1980 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Amish - memorandums concerning Amish school controversy (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Amnesty (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Amnesty (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Anglican (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Animals (Box 43, Folder 24)
    24a. Anonymity
  - Anti-Americanism (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - Anti-Defamation League (ADL) of B'nai B'rith - minutes, 1980-1983 (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Anti-Defamation League (ADL) of B'nai B'rith - reports, 1953-1972 (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - Anti-Discrimination Law (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Anti-Discrimination Legislation (Box 44, Folder 2)
    American Civil Liberties Union's legislative goals, 1964, not for public release
  - Anti-Riot Act (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Anti-Mask Legislation (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Anti-Semitism (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Anti-Semitism (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Anti-Semitism (Box 44, Folder 7)
    Status of Jews in Soviet Union; report, "Analysis of Jobs Held by Jewish and Non-Jewish Graduates of Harvard University Graduate School of Business Administration"
  - Anti-Semitism (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Anti-Semitism, 1966-1974 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    Minutes, 1974 meeting of the Seminar on Jewish Studies; report to the Advisory Community Relations Advisory Council of the Anti-Defamation League on the five-year study on anti-Semitism in the United States, 1966; statement of the Special Committee on Racial and Religious Prejudice; report of the American Jewish Committee Institute of Human Relations on Jews in college and university administration, 1966.
  - Anti-Semitism, 1947 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    Report of the Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith on anti-Semitism in the United States in 1947
  - Anti-Semitism (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Anti-Semitism, 1980 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    Address delivered by Kalman Sultanik to the International Council, Yad Vashem, 1980
  - Anti-Trust (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Apalachin Indictment (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Apartheid (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Appalachia Regional Development (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Apprenticeship (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Arab, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 18)
    Confidential report: "Meeting with New Left Faculty Members;" confidential report: "Arab Propaganda on Campus," by Alfred Jospe, 1969
  - Arabs (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Arab Boycott (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Arab Boycott (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Aramco (Arabian American Oil Company) (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Arbitration, 1951 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    "ILR 560 Case Studies for Classroom Use Only," Professor G.W. Brooks' Summer Session, 1951.
  - Arbitration (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Arbitration (Box 45, Folder 6)
    6a. Handwritten Notes on Arbitration
  - Area Development Legislation (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Arendt, Hannah (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Armband Case (Tinker) (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Arms (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Armed Forces (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Arraignment (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Arrest (Box 45, Folder 13)
    Report, "Benevolent Coercion: Arresting People for their Own Good" by Ira Glasser, Executive Director of the New York Civil Liberties Union
  - Arrest and Records (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Arts (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Arts - State Aid (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Asch, S.E. (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Ascoli, Max (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Asian Trade Union College (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Asociacion De Amigos Del Pais (Box 46, Folder 4)
    History of Organization; memorandum to Frank V. Ortiz, American Chamber of Commerce in Guatemala, from Thomas W. Mooney, President of the American Chamber of Commerce in Guatemala, regarding the effect of political instability on foreigners' perceptions; copy of telex from Edward Carrettee, American Chamber of Commerce of Guatemala, regarding political unrest in Guatemala.
  - Assembly (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Association (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Association - Handwritten bibliography, Konvitz (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Association for Jewish Studies (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Association, Freedom of (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Association: International Labor Conference (ILO) (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Association: National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Asylum (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Atlanta Project, 1962-1963 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    "Consensus," 1962-1963, Industrial and Labor Relations student publication, "Georgia on My Mind: the Atlanta Project Reconsidered," by Daniel Schecter
  - Atomic Energy (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Atomic Energy (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Attainder (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Attempts (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Attorney General (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - Attorneys (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Auden, W.H., 1956 (Box 46, Folder 20)
    "Making, Knowing, and Judging," an Inaugural lecture delivered before the University of Oxford, 1956
  - Audio-Visual, 1950 (Box 46, Folder 21)
    "Pencil-Work: The Story of Labor Management Relations In the American Lead Pencil Company," play
  - Australia (Box 46, Folder 22)
  - Automation (Box 46, Folder 23)
  - Automation (Box 46, Folder 24)
  - Auto Workers (Box 46, Folder 25)
  - Automobiles and Traffic (Box 46, Folder 26)
  - Autonomy (Box 46, Folder 27)
  - Automobiles (Box 46, Folder 28)
  - Babel, Isaac (Box 46, Folder 29)
  - Back Pay (Box 46, Folder 30)
  - Background of Industrial and Labor Relations, 1948-1949 (Box 46, Folder 31)
    Course syllabi, fall of 1948 and 1949; syllabus, Economics 803: The Economics of Soviet Russia, fall and spring of 1949
  - Backlash (Box 46, Folder 32)
  - Baeck (Leo Baeck Institute) (Box 46, Folder 33)
  - Bail, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 34)
    Minutes, Due Process Committee, American Civil Liberties Union. March 9, 1966
  - Bakke (Box 46, Folder 35)
  - Bakke Case (Box 46, Folder 36)
  - Baldwin, James (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Baldwin, Roger (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Ball, Senator (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Bar (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Bar-Niv, Zvi H. (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Barenblatt (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Bargaining Unit and Bargaining Representative (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Barron, Harry (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Barron, Milton L. (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Bates, Madison C. (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Beatles (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Bebout, John E. (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Becker, Carl L. (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Berkeley, California (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Berlin Crisis (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Berlin Manifesto (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Bernaus - Challenge to Research in Humanities (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Berrigan (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Berrigan Case, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 19)
    1974 memorandum from Lou Blickman, Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, to Konvitz, regarding Ithaca College's move to hire Father Berrigan, organizer of the peace movement
  - Biafra (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Bible (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - Bible (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - Bible - Gideon, 1962 (Box 47, Folder 23)
    1962 memorandum from Theodore Leskes and Sol Rabkin, American Jewish Congress, Anti- Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, regarding Attorney General of Washington held illegal to distribute Gideon bibles in public schools and illegal to execute religious exercises in public schools.
  - Bible and Love (Box 47, Folder 24)
    Handwritten note about the Bible to himself by M. Konvitz; letter, 1958, to Konvitz from Rabbi Abraham J. Karp regarding the Bible and legal remedies; handwritten notes about biblical topics by Konvitz; 1958 Spring Syllabus, Development of American Ideals; handwritten notes about philosophy
  - Bible - Prayer (Box 47, Folder 25)
  - Bible Reading Cases, 1963 (Box 47, Folder 26)
  - Bible Reading and Gideons (Box 48, Folder 1)
    Letter from H.M. McPherson, Superintendent of schools, Napa, California, to Konvitz, regarding the use of the Bible in public schools; list of schools where Bible reading is prohibited by statute or judicial constructions, schools where it is permitted, and schools where it is required
  - Bible reading, prayers, etcetera (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Bible Readings, etcetera in Schools (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Bigness (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Bilingual (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Bilingual (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Billboards (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Bills of Attainder (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Bills of Rights (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Bill of Rights Reader, 1955 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    1955 memorandum to Konvitz from Glendon A. Schubert, Junior, Professor at Michigan State, regarding the interpretation of a case in Konvitz's Bill of Rights Reader.
  - Birch, John, etcetera, 1964 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    1964 report, not for publication, by the American Jewish Committee, "The Politics of Prejudice: Wallace in the Presidential Primaries in Wisconsin, Indiana, and Maryland;" bibliography on political extremism in the United States
  - Birch Society (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Birth Control (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Birth Control (Box 48, Folder 14)
    memorandum not for distribution to the American Civil Liberties Union Board of Directors from the Due Process Committee regarding Compulsory Sterilization
  - Birth Control (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Birth Control (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Birth Control (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Birth Control (Box 48, Folder 18)
    Papal Encyclical
  - Blacks (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Blacks: Army (Military). (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Black Capitalism. (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Black Capitalism. (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Blacks: Demographic Changes. (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Blacks: Employment. (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Blacks: Family. (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Black History. (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Blacks: Jews. (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Blacks: Jury. (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Black, Justice Hugo. (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Blacks: Leadership. (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - "Black Manifesto", 1969 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    Policy statement from the Synagogue Council of America and the National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council, re the "Black Manifesto" of the Black Economic Development Conference.
  - Black, Max (Box 49, Folder 13)
    Proposed program for the Arts College, 1959.
  - Black Muslims. (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Black Muslims and Black Power. (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Black Nationalism (or Separatism). (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Black Panther, 1970 (Box 49, Folder 17)
    Report, not for republication, by the Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith about the Black Panthers.
  - Black Panther (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Black Power. (Box 49, Folder 19)
    Carmichael and H. Rap Brown included
  - Black Power. (Box 49, Folder 20)
    Education of Blacks and Black Studies.
  - Black Power., 1965 (Box 49, Folder 21)
    Miscellaneous
  - Black Progress. (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - Black Progress. (Box 49, Folder 23)
  - Black Studies and Literature, 1969 (Box 49, Folder 24)
    Talkin' Black, pamphlet by Cornell University students; "What are Black Studies?" excerpts from "Black Paper for Black Studies", a prospectus for a School for Black Studies at the University of Pittsburgh.
  - Blacks: Suffrage. (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Blacks: Unions (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Copies of A. Philip Randolph and George Meany letters re housing discrimination during Virginia AFL-CIO Convention, 1961.
  - Blacklist. (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Blacklisting. (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Blasphemy. (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Blue Collar Workers. (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Blum, Yehuda Z. (Box 50, Folder 6a)
    Statement in the Security Council in Exercise of the Right of Reply by Blum, Israel's Representative to the United Nations
  - B'nai B'rith, 1951-1963 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    1951 memo, from: Theodore Leskes and Sol Rabkin, re: Tilley and Steward vs. IBEW, Local 35; 1951 memo, from: American Jewish Committee, re: "Nearby Churches" in resort advertising; 1951 memo, from: Sol Rabkin and Frances Levenson, re: Aftermath of the Sup
  - B'nai B'rith (Box 50, Folder 8)
    preliminary draft of Personnel Code, 1958.
  - B'nai B'rith, 1960-1963 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    1963 memo, To: Commission and Advisory Board on Adult Jewish Education and Members of the Publications Committee and "Jewish Heritage" Committee, from: Lily Edelmen, re: New Adult Jewish Education Commissioner, Milton Konvitz; letter from Alfred Jospe, on
  - B'nai B'rith, 1959-1961 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    Proposed and operating budgets, 1959; proposed budget, 1961.
  - Bond, Julian. (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Books. (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Book Prizes. (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Book Stores. (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Boulwarism. (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Boycott, 1958 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    The Secondary Boycott by Konvitz for "Labor Relations Law and Legislation"
  - Boycotts (Box 50, Folder 17)
    handwritten notes and citations by Konvitz about International boycotts specifically Arab/Israeli.
  - Boycotts. (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Brandeis. (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - Bricker Amendment. (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - Britain. (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Britain. (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Britain: Church and Schools. (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Britain, Prejudice in. (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - British Speeches of the Day. (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Bronfenbrenner, Urie F. (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Brown vs. Topeka. (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Buber, Professor Martin. (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Buddhism. (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Budget. (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Building Construction. (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Building Construction Industry. (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Building Industry. (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Burial. (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Burling, Temple. (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Burtt, E. A. (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Bussing, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - Bussing, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 18)
  - Bussing, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 19)
  - Bussing, 1974-1976 (Box 51, Folder 20)
  - Bussing, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 21)
  - Bussing, Schools. (Box 51, Folder 22)
  - Byrnes, James F. (Box 51, Folder 23)
  - California Department of Employment. (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - California Institute of Technology. (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - University of California. (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Calley, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    1971 memo, to Board of Directors, American Civil Liberties Union, re Civil liberties implications of the Calley case.
  - Calvinism. (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Cameron, J. M. (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Campaign for Political Rights (Box 52, Folder 6a)
  - Camps. (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Campus Unrest, 1969 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    Progress Report of the National Committee of the Causes and Prevention of Violence to President Lydon B. Johnson; "Agreement Among the Administration, the Faculty and the Student Body of Wilberforce University."
  - Campus Unrest, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    Statement by Alexander Heard, Chancellor of Vanderbilt University, on completion of his mission as Special Advisor to the President.
  - Campus Unrest, 1971-1973 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Campus Unrest: Cornell, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Campus Unrest: Official reports, Scranton. (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Canisius College. (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Cape Cod. (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Capital Punishment. (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Capital Punishment. (Box 52, Folder 16)
  - Capital Punishment. (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Capital Punishment. (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Capitalism. (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - Cardozo, M. A., 1958 (Box 52, Folder 20)
    "New York to Brussels: Roundabout July and August, 1958" by Michael, Alice, Michael (V), Julia, and A. Rebecca Cardozo.
  - Carmichael. (Box 52, Folder 21)
  - Carnegie Corporation. (Box 52, Folder 22)
  - Carter (Box 52, Folder 23)
    "Carter, Evangelism and Jews" by Rabbi Marc H. Tanenbaum of the American Jewish Committee.
  - Cartels. (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Case Co. Case (Box 53, Folder 2)
    Course materials for New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations course, Foundations of Law, involving C. I. Case Co. vs. National Labor Relations Board.
  - Cash Sickness. (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Catherwood, Martin P. (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Catholic. (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Catholic. (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Catholic. (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Catholic Church (Box 53, Folder 8)
    Report, "A Survey and Evaluation of Christian-Jewish Relationships Since Vatican Council II" by Rabbi Marc H. Tanenbaum, National Interreligious Affairs Director of the American Jewish Committee.
  - Catholic Church. (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Catholic: Religious Liberties. (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Catholic: Schools. (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Catholic Council, Jewish Schism, 1965 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    Excerpts from the proceedings of the Executive Committee of the National Community Relations Advisory Council, 1965, "Declarations of the Vatican Council: Some Implications for Jewish Community Relations."
  - CCI (Commission on Community Interrelations of the American Jewish Congress) Notebook (Box 53, Folder 13)
    See also Box 62, Folder 22
  - Censorship: General., 1938-1968 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    "Encyclopedia Britannica" description of "Censorship" by Milton R. Konvitz, 1968; the American Jewish Committee Questionnaire on Freedom of Expression; American Jewish Congress Case Histories on Censorship for Discussion; "Self-Regulation versus Censorshi
  - Censorship. (Box 53, Folder 15)
  - Censorship: 1953. (Box 53, Folder 16)
  - Censorship. (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Censorship. (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Censorship, Advertising. (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Censorship, Music. (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Censorship: Art, Music, Theatre. (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Censorship: Articles. (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Censorship: Articles. (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Censorship: Behind the Iron Curtain. (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Censorship: Bibliography, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    Newsletter, "Censorship News" published by the National Ad Hoc Committee Against Censorship, 1975.
  - Censorship Case. (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Censorship Case: Candy. (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Censorship: Central Intelligence Agency. (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Censorship: Colleges. (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Censorship: Citizen Groups, Self-Policing, 1965 (Box 54, Folder 14)
    Statement of purpose by the National League of Decency; memo, to: National Community Relations Advisory Council, from: Philip Johnson, re: "The Greatest Story Ever Told", (movie, 1965).
  - Censorship: Comics (Box 54, Folder 15)
    Pamphlet, "British Comics: An Appraisal" by Comics Campaign Council.
  - Censorship: Commissions. (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - Censorship: Contraceptives. (Box 54, Folder 17)
  - Censorship: Court Opinions. (Box 54, Folder 18)
  - Censorship: In the Courts and Legislatures. (Box 54, Folder 19)
  - Censorship: Crime and Delinquency. (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Censorship: Customs., 1965 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    Letter from Huntington Cairns, the National Gallery of Art to Konvitz about trends in Court reasoning concerning obscenity; letter from Ralph Kelly, Commissioner of Customs to Konvitz re Customs' censorship of imported books.
  - Censorship: Customs. (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Censorship: Dress. (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Censorship: Dress and Haircut. (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Censorship: Encyclopedia Britannica. (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Censorship Case: Eros. (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Censorship: Events. (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Censorship Case: Fanny Hill (Box 55, Folder 9)